How a Revolver Works:
Colt Python
A colt python is loaded by first
pulling the 'cylinder latch' to the rear.
This unlocks the cylinder by means
of the spring-loaded 'latch pin'.
The 'crane' is now able to swivel
the cylinder out of the frame.
Cartridges are then loaded
into all sixchambers.
The cylinder is then pushed backinto the frame
and then rotated to ensure
the 'bolt' has locked it into position.
Many revolvers feature both
double-action and single-action operation.
In double-action operation,
the 'trigger' is pulleduntil it cocks
and releases the hammer to fire.
In single-action operation,
the 'hammer' is drawnback to the cocked position,
and held by the sear.
Squeezing the trigger releases the hammer to fire.
As the trigger is pulled, the trigger pushes up on
the 'hammer strut', cocking the hammer.
As the hammerrotates,
the 'main spring' is compressed
by means ofthe 'hammer stirrup'
and the 'rebound lever'
which ispushed up by the trigger.
As the hammer reachesits cocked position,
it slips off the trigger.
Simultaneously the trigger pushes down on the'bolt',
dropping it out of the cylinder pocket.
The 'hand' engages the ratchet of the cylinderejector,
indexing it to the next chamber.
Just as the hammer is released, the bolt drops into
the next pocket, locking the cylinders rotation.
At the same time, the trigger raises the
'transfer bar' up behind the firing pin.
As the hammer is released,
it strikesthe transfer bar,
transferring itsenergy to the firing pin,
which travels forward,impacting the 'cartridge primer'.
This detonatesthe priming compound and ignites
the powdercharge, propelling the bullet down the barrel.
With the rebound lever under constant
tension from the main spring,
its tensionis transferred to the trigger.
Releasing the trigger,
pivots the'hammer strut' out of the way,
allowingit to return to its forward position.
During single-action operation,
thehammer is pulled back,
driving movementof the trigger.
At its peak, the trigger
rests on the sear surface of the hammer.
Pulling the trigger, releases it from the hammer sear,
allowing it to strike the transfer bar.
Releasing the trigger,
againresets its forward position.
To eject the empty shell cases,
thecylinder latch is pulled,
allowing thecylinder to swivel out of the frame.
Holding the revolver in a verticalorientation
and pushing the 'ejector rod',
forces the cases out of the cylinder.
How a Revolver Works:
Colt Python
Modeling, Texturing, Animation
Matt Rittman
Voiceover
Andy Taylor
Music
Cinematic Electronic • MadStudioMusic
Special Thanks
Colter Brög
Created with Cinema 4D, Redshift,
After Effects, Substance 3D Painter, & Rizom UV.